<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain on Kaliban&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://kaliban2056.github.io/tags/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchain on Kaliban&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:56:55 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kaliban2056.github.io/tags/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://kaliban2056.github.io/posts/an-introduction-to-cryptocurrencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:56:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kaliban2056.github.io/posts/an-introduction-to-cryptocurrencies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is the first in a series designed to help beginners understand cryptocurrencies and the underlying technology that powers them, such as blockchain. Cryptocurrencies are a new way of exchanging value online without the need for intermediaries like banks or financial institutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ll start by exploring the basics of blockchain technology and how it applies to popular cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin.&#xA;What is Blockchain?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is a decentralized system for recording information. Unlike traditional systems where data is stored in a single place, blockchain keeps copies of its records across many computers (nodes), which makes it more secure and tamper-resistant. Here are the key features:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a New Blog Series on Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://kaliban2056.github.io/posts/introducing-a-new-blog-series-on-cryptocurrencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 11:35:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kaliban2056.github.io/posts/introducing-a-new-blog-series-on-cryptocurrencies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce a new series of posts where I&amp;rsquo;ll be diving into the world of cryptocurrencies and everything that comes with them. From how Bitcoin and Ethereum work to exploring decentralized finance (DeFi), blockchain technology, NFTs, and much more – this series will cover a wide range of topics related to digital currencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-to-expect&#34;&gt;What to Expect&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies are transforming how we think about finance, technology, and even the ownership of digital assets. Whether you’re new to crypto or looking to deepen your understanding, I’ll be covering topics such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
